Hello friends, my name is Vinod Kumar
and welcome again to the new video. So in today
's video I am going to tell you that for
how long is the first party insurance and for
how long is the third party insurance. Well,
everyone must know the basics that this
whole total timing is of 5 years,
in which there is an insurance system by doing four years third party and one year
first party.
So some things which I had mentioned
in the previous video were not clear
and some people are
not getting it clear again and again, I have also replied to the comments
but a lot of questions are being
asked in it again and again, so I thought that
a proper video should be made for you on it
and all the doubts of everyone should be
cleared. As it has been
asked again and again that can I get the insurance done
from anywhere, means will I have to
go to the agency or where? Many more
questions have been asked like how much premium will it cost
or if I have first party then should I take third
party or if I have third party then should I
take first party or not,
many such questions have been asked by people, so
today I am going to make a video in full detail on that,
every comment  I had read it and
replied to people, but it is
also important to make videos. Some people might not know, so
they will get to know by watching the video. So
let's start the video. First of all,
I would like to answer the latest comment that you received. In that,
they had asked that for how
long is the first party insurance, that is, the total insurance of 5 years, that is, they had
asked something like this, whether it is 1 year plus 4 years or
1 year plus 5 years, so
one year plus 5 years means that the
third party is for the entire 5 years and the
first party for one year. So, they had
asked something like this, so I would
like to answer that your insurance is
one year plus 5 years, 1 year
means that your insurance, the
first party insurance will be valid
along with it, your third party
insurance will also be valid, so that is what it is. Now you might have a
little doubt about what is the
proper meaning of first party and third party. So, first
party insurance in this is on damage,
that is, for your own damage also.  You will get cover
and in third party insurance it is only
for the person who has met with an accident in front of you
and only he will get it, you are
not going to get anything so this is the difference between first party and third
party this is called
first party on damage means Audi is
also called and third party is also
called third party so this is the difference between both
and the first party is
for only one year and the
third party is for full 5 years it is
okay that some people will have doubt that for one
year it will be first party and
not third party so it is not like that third
party is also there along with it and first
party because if your stand is there then
you will also get it i.e. money and
whatever claim etc. is there and so the
third party which is the person in front of you is
also going to get it i.e. you will get the cover
and this is just a
first party the rest of the entire system is
of third party so the first
question which has been asked repeatedly is
that the
cost of my bike means the cost of the bike is
₹1 lakh then how much will its first party be
renewed  What will happen, so
as I told you, in the first
party renewal, the
value of the bike is always the value of your new bike, for example, it is ₹1 lakh, and right now the
value of your bike does
not always remain the same, the value of your bike
decreases as soon as it leaves the showroom,
so understand that the value of your bike
was ₹1 lakh in the showroom, and right now the
value of your bike is around 80000, so
you understand that if
you paid ₹2000 for ₹1 lakh, and
then you will pay the same percentage for ₹80000, so what it
means is that you have to pay according to the value of your bike, or
it is
according to some percentage of the value, so you can understand from this,
and I cannot explain it to you in detail,
but I can give you some idea
that if the bike is worth ₹1 lakh, then
how much was your neem insurance, and if the
bike is worth ₹80000, then  How much will your re-insurance cost?
Insurance does
n't necessarily have a fixed amount.
Insurance can have different prices
because some of the
facilities are provided to you, some are more, some are
good, some are more, the
maintenance charges of the bike, etc.,
some of the facilities are more, so the
rates can go up or down accordingly, so it depends on
which insurance you take. The
next question I would like to tell you is that
people have asked whether I
can get my insurance done from anywhere or do
I have to go to an agency. It is not like that, if
you don't go to an agency then there is no
problem, you can get your insurance done from anywhere, it is
also done online,
nowadays there are many companies like
Flipkart, PhonePe and
many more from all over the world, every company, every bank
also has an online system and if you don't understand online then
you can go and get it done from any bank,
you will get it easily from the bank,
go to any bank and get it done, there is an
insurance department there,
bike insurance, insurance, health
insurance, everything is available there.  It is
not necessary to get insurance done by
going to an agency if possible, you
can get it done by going to your nearby agency. If you
can get it done from an agency, you can get it done from there as well.
You will get the facility from both the places, it is
not compulsory to get it done from the agency. One question is similar to the
first question in this also
people have asked the same thing that if I got my
insurance done, suppose you got
your insurance done from
ICICI first and now you have got your insurance done
from HDFC, then there is a difference between the two,
earlier your insurance was from ICICI and now
from HDFC, people are
confused in this also that how can this happen, I
mean I will pay the premium in this, will
I get a claim in it or
not, so let me tell you the first thing that
you will get a claim in this, you will get it
100%, the one
from HDFC will be a first party claim
and the one from ICICI,
Johnson, the second old insurance is
running for 5 years, in that you are going to get
insurance from the third party, so it is
not that you will not get the premium,
some people think that it means from the second insurance  There will be no
problem, it is not like that, this one will do its work,
you should take
5 years of insurance, in this the
company benefits as much as you have kept,
so the company will keep giving you insurance
and whenever there is any damage to you,
you can take a claim
and the final and the last question which I also
think you should tell, only a few
people had asked that and they say that if
I do not get the insurance renewed,
like I have a 5 year insurance, out of which
one year of my first party has ended
and the remaining four years are left, then if I am
not renewing it, will I face any problem,
so look brother, it is a simple thing,
use your common sense yourself that if you do not have
insurance, will you face any
problem or not, or you
can understand yourself like if I tell
you that you will definitely get the claim on your first party insurance,
okay,
otherwise you will not get any claim on your bike in third party,
whether it gets stolen or if it gets broken or you get
injured, then in this you will easily
escape from the police.  Looking at it, it means that
for them it is insurance only, a claim can be made in it to a
third party, so there is
insurance in it, but you and I are
not going to get anything in it, so that is why I
say that making a difference is compulsory, if you get it done then everything will be
fine, otherwise if you don't get it done then there is
police, then you will be saved,
as it happens, some people do not have money, so they
can do it for some time,
but you should get the insurance done as soon as possible
so that you do not face any problem in the future, I
hope
I must have replied to all your comments and those who had even a little
complaint with this video or the information was mismatched,
all that must have been cleared through this video, so we will
meet you in the next video, till then
bye-bye and before leaving,
like the video,
subscribe to the channel if you have gained anything from the information given by me.